Benjamin F. Wilson

Bürgermeister-Schwiening Strasse 36, Aurich, Lower Saxony, DE wilson.f.benjamin@gmail.com (*pref*) | 1-415-246-6278 | www.uphouseworks.com | github.com/montymxb

Summary

Recent MS and BS graduate in Computer Science from Oregon State University, and former Head Software Engineer at Axolsoft in California. Specializing in full-stack, front-end, and server-side engineering. Passionate about building systems that help others learn, discover information, and just generally make people smile. Background in biology and mechanical engineering. Interested in applications related to data visualization, tools for data analysis, and programming language design and development.

Skills

- Proficient: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Haskell, C++, C, Bash, RegEx, full-stack & front-end engineering, testing, CI
- Familiar: Python, Typescript, Lua, GLSL, Java, MySQL, x86 Assembly, Obj-C, networking, ML, general biology
- Technologies: NGINX, AWS, OpenGL, React, Node.js, Git/Github, Unix, Windows, Android, iOS, LATEX

Experience

Research Assistant, Programming Languages Group, Oregon State University 2020 - 2021

- Worked under Prof. Martin Erwig to research classification and ordering systems for educational programming examples
- Designed technique for classifying programs into teachable partial-orderings via graphs, using syntactic categories
- Co-wrote the programming language BoGL in Haskell, and engineered the BoGL stack with Haskell/NGINX/React on AWS
- Led development on the research group website in Hugo, BoGL documentation/tutorials using Jekyll, and BoGL interpreters

Teaching Assistant, Oregon State University

Sept. 2018 - June 2020

- Taught students in introductory Computer Science 160/162 courses to teach concepts through C++ & Haskell
- Ran labs with students, graded assignments, provided office hours, and volunteered to run after-hours study sessions
- Helped guide evolution of the introductory CS courses with fellow TAs and instructors over many terms

Core Contributor, Parse Community on Github

Jan. 2017 - June 2018

- Oversaw the Parse PHP SDK (akin to Firebase), performed code reviews, and lead testing & development
- Improved the SDK through > 90% test coverage, style enforcement, integrated Travis CI, and auto-generated documentation
- Performed code reviews, helped onboard new contributors, and worked with developers from across the world

Head Software Engineer, Axolsoft, Upland CA

Jan. 2015 - Sept. 2017

- Co-founded Axolsoft LLC and built full-stack, front-end, Android and iOS applications
- Built & managed CMS, e-commerce, and email marketing systems in PHP/SQL for private and government clients
- Contributed patches on Github to the Braintree PHP and Parse PHP SDKs, both being used at Axolsoft

Web and Mobile Development, Contract

2013 - 2017

- Used HTML5, PHP, Apache, and Braintree Payments for the online portal and website for Score Savers SAT Prep
- Engineered Android & iOS (Java & Obj-C) student testing apps for Score Savers with SQLite, CoreData, MySQL and PHP
- Built parent portal in PHP to manage student accounts, enrolled programs, and payments via the Braintree PHP SDK

Education

M.S. - Computer Science, Oregon State University (OSU), Corvallis OR, 3.91 GPA 2020 - 2021

Studied Programming Language Theory, Computer Graphics, AI

B.S. - Computer Science, OSU, Corvallis OR, Cum Laude, 3.59 GPA

2018 - 2020

Mechanical Engineering, OSU, Corvallis, OR

2011 - 2012

San Marin HS, Novato, CA

2011